Kuan-Yu Lai Email: laik@oregonstate.edu Mobile: +1-971-985-5375

Personal Page: http://web.engr.oregonstate.edu/ $\sim laik$

Github: https://github.com/KuanYuLai

PROFILE

I am an extremely hard-working, friendly and creative person. I really enjoy working with peers ever since I was a junior high school student. I have been programming for more than 10 years and had received multiple awards base on both programming skills and teamwork. Right now, I mainly focusing on back-end development but exploring new technology and problem-solving will remain my love and interest in my life.

EDUCATION

Oregon State University

Corvallis, OR

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science Overall GPA: 2.86 Major GPA: 3.2

Sep. 2015 - June. 2020

EXPERIENCE

GoGreatMoods

Minneapolis, MN

Software Internship

June 2019 - October 2019

Working with the 5 members software engineer team during summer. Our job is to fix the broken functionality and patching the website interface. The languages we use are HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Electric Logistics LLC

Corvallis, OR

CTO

June 2017 - June 2019

The company creates battery adapters that can transfer AAA or AA battery into C or D battery. In the company I am responsible for R&D and website management, the website is mainly for selling the product.

Graphene Security Ltd. Taiwan Branch

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Software Internship

June 2014 - September 2015

Helping the IT department to create an Android App that allows the customer to control the light of the panel, product of them, imitating sun rise and fall. The first prototype is created by AppInventor and than Android Studio.

Current Project

• Smart Job Advisor: Back-end with HP: Building a setting evaluation system for the HP industrial printing presses. The system takes the settings from the users from the front-end and evaluates based on the pre-defined rules. Eventually, generate the recommended settings for the user. In this project, I am responsible for the back-end which is the rules engine and the RESTful API that interact with the front-end. The rules engine is built with the j-easy rules engine and the RESTful API is built with Node.js. Currently, the system hosted on the AWS EC2 server.

Projects

- NCAA Baseball player Search Engine: A search engine specifically for limited NCAA baseball player
- ZombieApocalypse: A web application that allows you to set your exercise goal and report the health information based on the given data
- Weather indicator app: Weather forecasting website that for United State

AWARDS

- Champion: TTRA Robot Design Class Youth Group 2013/7/14
- 8th Place: FLL Selective Trial in Taiwan 2013/3/3
- Champion: WRO National Finals 2012/5/30

Programming Skills

- Technologies: AWS, Git, Docker, Node.js, React, MongoDB, Android
- Languages: C/C++, Assembly, Python, Java/JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, LaTeX
- Operating System: Windows, MacOS, Linux